# Rae Wong Ying Yee

Systems and Machine Learning

#### **Senior Thesis**

#### "Optimizing Adaptive Machine Learning computation on Heterogeneous Devices"

My final year research thesis explores the distribution and parallelism of adaptive machine learning computation. I was motivated to build an optimized heterogeneous system after noticing the correlation between the activation of different compute units. This correlation can be leveraged to distribute workload in both compilation and run-time. I believe with the current development of GPUs, taking advantage of heterogeneous architecture, on top of existing optimization techniques such as FlexFlow, can achieve a substantial speedup.

# Work Experience

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022 (sg)

Open Government Products

Software Engineering Intern open source customize-and-broadcast product

- Automated E2E smoke tests using Cypress, Gmail API and Twilio API and integrated them into the CI/CD pipeline, reducing deployment time by 20%.
- Built a custom html converter to enable copy-and-pasting of styles from MS Word to our rich text editor based off the Draft.js framework by Meta.
- Introduced search and sort functions on dashboard to enhance user experience.

JAN 2022 - CURRENT (US)

Carnegie Mellon University

**Teaching Assistant** 15-210: Parallel and Sequential Data Structures and Algorithms

- Teach parallel algorithms using functional programming in a core CS class.
- · Hold recitations and office hours to clarify any doubts and provide feedback readily.

APR 202I - DEC 202I (us)

Carnegie Mellon University

ML Research Assistant Computer Music Lab

- Developed a model for music prediction and to further extract repetition patterns.
- Implemented Variable Order Markov Models to improve prediction results by 30%.
- Conducted confidence weighting to dynamically blend foreground and background learning, boosting accuracy by 10%.

 $AUG\ 2O2O-SEP\ 2O2O\ \ (sG)$ 

Insignia Ventures Partners

Software Engineering Intern Web development

- · Created a VC simulator to visualizes ownership division per series of funding.
- Deployed an interactive version of the simulator as an online compute tool for all and benefited over 50 international startups by flagging out risks of fund raising.

JAN 2020 - MAR 2020 (sg)

Government Technology Agency

Computer Security Intern IoT - Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE)

- Researched on BLE to ensure security of Trace Together, a Covid-19 contact tracing app, protecting privacy of millions of users.
- Led testing of bluetooth devices and drafted nationwide security standards.
- · Demonstrated XSS attack on an IoT system to heighten awareness of vulnerabilities.

JAN 2017 - JAN 2019 (sg)

Agency for Science, Technology and Research

**Research Assistant** System Security and Machine Learning

- Designed and implemented a software to configure Linux iptables firewall with ease.
- Customized the product to protect the nation's transport infrastructure, by supporting the Modbus protocol and filtering of proprietary instruction codes.
- Expanded it into a robust Intrusion Detection System using semi-supervised machine learning to reduce reliance on rule-based detection and manual work.

Pittsburgh, PA, US
(412) 482-8489
yingyeeoii@gmail.com
in linkedin.com/in/raeyy

#### Education

2023 – 24 M.Sc. in Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University Catalyst Research Group

2020 – 23 B.Sc. in Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University DEAN'S LIST HIGH HONORS GPA 4.0/4.0

2018 – 19 Cambridge A-Levels
TOP IN COMPUTING
7 Distinctions

#### **Courses**

15897

Design and Analysis of Algorithms
Probability and Computing
Distributed Systems
Computer Architecture
Programming Language Pragmatics

Parallelism and Concurrency

16385 Computer Vision18330 Computer Security

### **Skills**

LANGUAGES C, Java, Python
Standard ML
Javascript, Typescript
TOOLS OpenCV
Node.js
ReactJS
HTML/CSS

## Extracurriculars

2022 **Outreach Coordinator** CMU Project Smile

2022 **Teaching Volunteer**Epworth Community Services

2019 **Co-Chairperson**International Science Youth Forum

## **Awards**

Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship, Carnegie Mellon University

**Bronze**, Science and Engineering Research Fair

**Joint First in Nationals**, International Mathematical Modelling Challenge

**Championship and Best Defender**, Cyber Defenders Camp CTF